<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://wangyenshu.github.io/arxiv-feed/index.html</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.357Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://wangyenshu.github.io/arxiv-feed/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://wangyenshu.github.io/arxiv-feed/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comparing Bushnell-Kutzko and S\'echerre's constructions of types for $\mathrm{GL}_{N}$ and its inner forms with Yu's construction]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2112.12367v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2112.12367"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.332Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2112.12367v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Let $F$ be a non-archimedean local field, $A$ be a central simple $F$-algebra, and $G$ be the multiplicative group of $A$. To construct types for supercuspidal representations of $G$, simple types by S\'echerre and Yu's construction are already known. In this paper, we compare these constructions. In particular, we show essentially tame supercuspidal representations of $G$ defined by Bushnell-Henniart are nothing but tame supercuspidal representations defined by Yu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Arnaud Mayeux, Yuki Yamamoto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Non-Expanding Random walks on Homogeneous spaces and Diophantine approximation]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2406.15824v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.15824"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.199Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2406.15824v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We study non-expanding random walks on the space of affine lattices and establish a new classification theorem for stationary measures. Further, we prove a theorem that relates the genericity with respect to these random walks to Birkhoff genericity. Finally, we apply these theorems to obtain several results in inhomogeneous Diophantine approximation, especially on fractals.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Aggarwal, Anish Ghosh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boundedness of the p-primary torsion of the Brauer group of products of varieties]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2404.19150v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.19150"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.194Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2404.19150v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Let k be a field finitely generated over its prime subfield. We prove that the quotient of the Brauer group of a product of varieties over k by the Brauer groups of factors has finite exponent. The bulk of the proof concerns p-primary torsion in characteristic p. Our approach gives a more direct proof of the boundedness of the p-primary torsion of the Brauer group of an abelian variety, as recently proved by D'Addezio. We show that the transcendental Brauer group of a Kummer surface over k has finite exponent, but can be infinite when k is an infinite field of positive characteristic. This answers a question of Zarhin and the author.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexei N. Skorobogatov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generalization of Siegel's Method to theta 1]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2208.02168v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2208.02168"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.190Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2208.02168v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We present a new proof of the transformation law of $\vartheta_1$ under the action of the generator of the full modular group $\Gamma$ using Siegel's method.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maher Me'meh, Ali Saraeb</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quadratic enrichment of the logarithmic derivative of the zeta function]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2210.03035v5</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2210.03035"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.181Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2210.03035v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We define an enrichment of the logarithmic derivative of the zeta function of a variety over a finite field to a power series with coefficients in the Grothendieck--Witt group. We show that this enrichment is related to the topology of the real points of a lift. For cellular schemes over a field, we prove a rationality result for this enriched logarithmic derivative of the zeta function as an analogue of part of the Weil conjectures. We also compute several examples, including toric varieties, and show that the enrichment is a motivic measure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Margaret Bilu, Wei Ho, Padmavathi Srinivasan, Isabel Vogt, Kirsten Wickelgren</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CMC surfaces of revolution, Elliptic curves, Weierstrass-$\wp$ functions, and Algebraicity]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2405.19742v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.19742"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.177Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2405.19742v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This paper establishes an interesting connection between the family of CMC surfaces of revolution in $\mathbb E_1^3$ and some specific families of elliptic curves. As a consequence of this connection, we show in the class of spacelike CMC surfaces of revolution in the $\mathbb E_1^3$, only spacelike cylinders and standard hyperboloids are algebraic. We also show that a similar connection exists between CMC surfaces of revolution in $\mathbb E^3$ and elliptic curves. Further, we use this to reestablish the fact that the only CMC algebraic surfaces of revolution in $\mathbb E^3$ are spheres and right circular cylinders.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rukmini Dey, Anantadulal Paul, Rahul Kumar Singh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ortho-integral surfaces]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2112.10694v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2112.10694"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.173Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2112.10694v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This paper introduces a combinatorial structure of orthogeodesics on hyperbolic surfaces and presents several relations among them. As a primary application, we propose a recursive method for computing the trace (the hyperbolic cosine of the length) of orthogeodesics and establish the existence of surfaces where the trace of each orthogeodesic is an integer. These surfaces and their orthogeodesics are closely related to integral Apollonian circle packings. Notably, we found a new type of root-flipping that transitions between roots in different quadratic Diophantine equations of a certain type, with Vieta root-flipping as a special case. Finally, we provide a combinatorial proof of Basmajian's identity for hyperbolic surfaces, akin to Bowditch's combinatorial proof of the McShane identity.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nhat Minh Doan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modular forms for the Weil representation induced from isotropic subgroups]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2312.01443v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.01443"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.146Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2312.01443v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: For an isotropic subgroup $H$ of a discriminant form $D$ there exists a lift from modular forms for the Weil representation of the discriminant form $H^\bot/H$ to modular forms for the Weil representation of $D$. We determine a set of discriminant forms such that all modular forms for any discriminant form are induced from the discriminant forms in this set. Furthermore for any discriminant form in this set there exist modular forms that are not induced from smaller discriminant forms.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Manuel K. -H. M\"uller</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finiteness properties of torsion fields of abelian varieties]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2401.05805v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05805"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.134Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2401.05805v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Let $A$ be an abelian variety defined over a field $K.$ We study finite generation properties of the profinite group $\mathrm{Gal}(\Omega/K)$ and of certain closed normal subgroups thereof, where $\Omega$ is the torsion field of $A$ over $K$. In fact, we establish more general finite generation properties for monodromy groups attached to smooth projective varieties via \'etale cohomology. We apply this in order to give an independent proof and generalizations of a recent result of Checcoli and Dill about small exponent subfields of $\Omega/K$ in the number field case. We also give an application of our finite generation results in the realm of permanence principles for varieties with the weak Hilbert property.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wojciech Gajda, Sebastian Petersen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ekedahl-Oort strata and the supersingular locus in the GU(q-2,2) Shimura variety]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2405.04464v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.04464"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.130Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2405.04464v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper concerns the characteristic-$p$ fibers of $\mathsf{GU}(q-2,2)$ Shimura varieties, which classify abelian varieties with additional structure. These Shimura varieties admit two stratifications of interest: the Ekedahl-Oort stratification, based on the isomorphism class of the $p$-torsion subgroup scheme, and the Newton stratification, based on the isogeny class of the $p$-divisible group. It is natural to ask which Ekedahl-Oort strata intersect the unique closed Newton stratum, called the supersingular locus. In this paper, we present several novel techniques that give information about the interaction between the two stratifications for general signature $(q-2,2)$, and as an application, we completely answer this question for the signature $(3,2)$.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emerald Anne, Deewang Bhamidipati, Maria Fox, Heidi Goodson, Steven Groen, Sandra Nair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the dynamical Bogomolov conjecture for families of split rational maps]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2201.10455v4</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2201.10455"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.121Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2201.10455v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We prove that Zhang's dynamical Bogomolov conjecture holds uniformly along $1$-parameter families of rational split maps and curves. This provides dynamical analogues of recent results of Dimitrov-Gao-Habegger and K\"uhne. In fact, we prove a stronger Bogomolov-type result valid for families of split maps in the spirit of the relative Bogomolov conjecture. We thus provide first instances of a generalization of a conjecture by Baker and DeMarco to higher dimensions. Our proof contains both arithmetic and analytic ingredients. We establish a characterization of curves that are preperiodic under the action of a non-exceptional split rational endomorphism $(f,g)$ of $(\mathbb{P}^1_{\mathbb{C}})^2$ with respect to the measures of maximal entropy of $f$ and $g$, extending a previous result of Levin-Przytycki. We further establish a height inequality for families of split maps and varieties comparing the values of a fiber-wise Call-Silverman canonical height with a height on the base and valid for most points of a non-preperiodic variety. This provides a dynamical generalization of a result by Habegger and generalizes results of Call-Silverman and Baker to higher dimensions. In particular, we establish a geometric Bogomolov theorem for split rational maps and varieties of arbitrary dimension.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Niki Myrto Mavraki, Harry Schmidt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modular forms with non-vanishing central values and linear independence of Fourier coefficients]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2307.00900v3</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2307.00900"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.117Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2307.00900v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this article, we are interested in modular forms with non-vanishing central critical values and linear independence of Fourier coefficients of modular forms. The main ingredient is a generalization of a theorem due to VanderKam to modular symbols of higher weights. We prove that for sufficiently large primes $p$, Hecke operators $T_1, T_2, \ldots, T_D$ act linearly independently on the winding elements inside the space of weight $2k$ cuspidal modular symbol $\mathbb{S}_{2k}(\Gamma_0(p))$ with $k\geq 1$ for $D^2\ll p$. This gives a bound on the number of newforms with non-vanishing arithmetic $L$-functions at their central critical points and linear independence on the reductions of these modular forms for prime modulo $l\not=p$.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Debargha Banerjee, Priyanka Majumder</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multiplicative largeness of $\textit{de Polignac numbers}$]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2406.02243v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.02243"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.113Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2406.02243v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: A number $m$ is said to be a $\textit{de Polignac number}$, if infinitely many pairs of consecutive primes exist, such that $m$ can be written as the difference of those consecutive prime numbers. Recently in [ W. D. Banks: Consecutive primes and IP sets, arXiv:2403.10637.], using arguments from the Ramsey theory, W. D. Banks proved that the collection of $\textit{de Polignac number}$ is an $IP^\star$ set (Though his original statement is relatively weaker, an iterative application of pigeonhole principle/ theory of ultrafilters shows that this statement is sufficient to conclude the set is $IP^\star$). As a consequence, we have this collection as an additively syndetic set. In this article, we show that this collection is also a multiplicative syndetic set. In our proof, we use combinatorial arguments and the tools from the algebra of the Stone-\v{C}ech compactification of discrete semigroups (for details see [N. Hindman, and D. Strauss: Algebra in the Stone-\v{C}ech Compactification: Theory and Applications, second edition, de Gruyter, Berlin,2012.]).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sayan Goswami</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Least zero of a cubic form]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2404.00518v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.00518"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.102Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2404.00518v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: An explicit upper bound is established for the least non-trivial integer zero of an arbitrary cubic form $C \in \mathbb{Z}[X_1,...,X_n],$ provided that $n \geq 14.$]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yixiu Xiao, Hongze Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monodromy groups and exceptional Hodge classes]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2405.20394v3</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.20394"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.097Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2405.20394v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Denote by $J_m$ the Jacobian variety of the hyperelliptic curve defined by the affine equation $y^2=x^m+1$ over $\mathbb{Q}$, where $m \geq 3$ is a fixed positive integer. We compute several interesting arithmetic invariants of $J_m$: its decomposition up to isogeny into simple abelian varieties, the minimal field $\mathbb{Q}(\operatorname{End}(J_m))$ over which its endomorphisms are defined, its connected monodromy field $\mathbb{Q}(\varepsilon_{J_m})$, and its Sato-Tate group. Currently, there is no general algorithm that computes these last two invariants. Furthermore, for large enough values of $m$, the abelian varieties $J_m$ provide non-trivial examples of high-dimensional phenomena, such as degeneracy and the non-triviality of the extension $\mathbb{Q}(\varepsilon_{J_m})/\mathbb{Q}(\operatorname{End}(J_m))$. We also describe the Sato-Tate group of an abelian variety, generalizing existing results that apply only to non-degenerate varieties, and prove an extension of a well-known formula of Gross-Koblitz that relates values of the classical and $p$-adic gamma functions at rational arguments.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrea Gallese, Heidi Goodson, Davide Lombardo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An analogue of a conjecture of Rasmussen and Tamagawa for abelian varieties over function fields]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2310.11100v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.11100"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.093Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2310.11100v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Let $L$ be a number field and let $\ell$ be a prime number. Rasmussen and Tamagawa conjectured, in a precise sense, that abelian varieties whose field of definition of the $\ell$-power torsion is both a pro-$\ell$ extension of $L(\mu_\ell)$ and unramified away from $\ell$ are quite rare. In this paper, we formulate an analogue of the Rasmussen--Tamagawa conjecture for non-isotrivial abelian varieties defined over function fields. We provide a proof of our analogue in the case of elliptic curves. In higher dimensions, when the base field is a subfield of the complex numbers, we show that our conjecture is a consequence of the uniform geometric torsion conjecture. Finally, using a theorem of Bakker and Tsimerman we also prove our conjecture unconditionally for abelian varieties with real multiplication.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mentzelos Melistas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First moment of central values of quadratic Dirichlet $L$-functions]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2303.11588v3</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.11588"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.090Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2303.11588v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We evaluate the first moment of central values of the family of quadratic Dirichlet $L$-functions using the method of double Dirichlet series. Under the generalized Riemann hypothesis, we prove an asymptotic formula with an error term of size that is the fourth root of that of the primary main term.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peng Gao, Liangyi Zhao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tournament score sequences, Erd\H{o}s-Ginzburg-Ziv numbers, and the L\'evy-Khintchine method]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.01441v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.01441"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.053Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.01441v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We give a short proof of a recent result of Claesson, Dukes, Frankl\'in and Stef\'ansson, that connects tournament score sequences and the Erd\H{o}s-Ginzburg-Ziv numbers from additive number theory. We show that this connection is, in fact, an instance of the L\'evy-Khintchine formula from probability theory, and highlight how such formulas can be useful in enumerative combinatorics. Our proof combines renewal theory with the representation of score sequences as lattice paths, due to Erd\H{o}s and Moser in the 1960s. These probabilistic and geometric points of view lead to a simpler proof. A key idea in the original proof and ours is to consider cyclic shifts of score sequences. We observe, however, that this idea is already present in Kleitman's remarks added to one of Moser's final articles in 1968, and in subsequent works by Kleitman. In the same article, Moser conjectured that there are asymptotically $C4^n/n^{5/2}$ many score sequences of length $n$. Combining the arguments in the current work with those in a recent work by the third author, we demonstrate the utility of the L\'evy-Khintchine method, by giving a short proof of Moser's conjecture.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michal Bassan, Serte Donderwinkel, Brett Kolesnik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generalized Motives through Witt Vectors]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.01417v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.01417"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.047Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.01417v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We generalize condensed motives, through Witt vectors and the associated moduli stacks of generalized line bundles.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xin Tong</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heights and periods of algebraic cycles in families]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.01304v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.01304"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:32.020Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.01304v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We consider the Beilinson--Bloch heights and Abel--Jacobian periods of homologically trivial Chow cycles in families. For the Beilinson--Bloch heights, we show that for any $g\ge 2$, there is a Zariski open dense subset $U$ of $\mathcal{M}_g$, the coarse moduli of curves of genus $g$ over rationals, such that the heights of Ceresa cycles and Gross--Schoen cycles over $U$ satisfy the Northcott property. For the Abel--Jacobi periods, we provide an algebraic criterion for the existence of a Zariski open dense subset of any family such that all cycles not defined over $\overline{\mathbb{Q}}$ are non-torsion and verify that this criterion holds for Ceresa cycles and Gross--Schoen cycles.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ziyang Gao, Shou-Wu Zhang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tannakian fundamental groups of blended extensions]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.01379v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.01379"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.857Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.01379v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Let $A_1, A_2,A_3$ be semisimple objects in a neutral tannakian category over a field of characteristic zero. Let $L$ be an extension of $A_2$ by $A_1$, and $N$ an extension of $A_3$ by $A_2$. Let $M$ be a blended extension (extension panach\'ee) of $N$ by $L$. Under very mild and natural hypotheses, we study the unipotent radical of the tannakian fundamental group of $M$. Examples where our results apply include the unipotent radicals of motivic Galois groups of any mixed motive with three weights.
  As an application, we give a proof of the unipotent part of the Hodge-Nori conjecture for 1-motives (which is now a theorem of Andr\'e in the setting of Nori motives) in the setting of any tannakian category of motives where the group $Ext^1(1,\mathbb{Q}(1))$ is as expected.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Payman Eskandari</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disproving a weaker form of Hooley's conjecture]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.01045v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.01045"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.781Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.01045v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Hooley conjectured that $G(x;q) \ll x\log q$, as soon as $q\to +\infty$, where $G(x;q)$ represents the variance of primes $p \leq x$ in arithmetic progressions modulo $q$, weighted by $\log p$. In this paper, we study $G_\eta(x;q)$, a function similar to $G(x;q)$, but including the weighting factor $\eta\left(\frac{p}{x}\right)$, which has a dampening effect on the values of $G_\eta$. Our study is motivated by the disproof of Hooley's conjecture by Fiorilli and Martin in the range $q \asymp \log \log x$. Even though this weighting factor dampens the values, we still prove that an estimation of the form $G_\eta(x;q) \ll x\log q$ is false in the same range.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mounir Hayani (IMB)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Local-global principle for groups of type An over semi global fields]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.00726v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00726"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.733Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.00726v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Let F be the function field of a curve over a complete discretely valued field K. Let G be a semisimple simply connected linear algebraic group over F of type An. We give a description of the obstruction to local global principle for principal homogeneous spaces under G over F with respect to discrete valuations of F in terms of R-equivalence classes of G over some suitable over fields. Using this description we prove that this obstruction vanishes under some conditions on the residue field K.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>V. Suresh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Packing density of sets with only two non-mixed gaps]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.01101v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.01101"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.725Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.01101v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: For a finite set of integers such that the first few gaps between its consecutive elements equal $a$, while the remaining gaps equal $b$, we study dense packings of its translates on the line. We obtain an explicit lower bound on the corresponding optimal density, conjecture its tightness, and prove it in case one of the gap lengths, $a$ or $b$, appears only once. This is equivalent to a Motzkin problem on the independence ratio of certain integer distance graphs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexander Natalchenko, Arsenii Sagdeev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Rankin-Selberg integral structures and Euler systems for $\mathrm{GL}_2\times \mathrm{GL}_2$]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.01377v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.01377"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.717Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.01377v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We study how Rankin-Selberg periods interact with integral structures in spherical Whittaker type representations. Using this representation-theoretic framework, we show that the local Euler factors appearing in the construction of the motivic Rankin-Selberg Euler system for a product of modular forms are integrally optimal; i.e. any construction of this type with any choice of integral input data would give local factors appearing in tame norm relations at $p$ which are integrally divisible by the Euler factor $\mathcal{P}_p^{'}(\mathrm{Frob}_p^{-1})$ modulo $p-1$.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexandros Groutides</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twisted traces of modular functions on hyperbolic $3$-space]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.01368v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.01368"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.707Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.01368v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We compute analogues of twisted traces of CM values of harmonic modular functions on hyperbolic $3$-space and show that they are essentially given by Fourier coefficients of the $j$-invariant. From this we deduce that the twisted traces of these harmonic modular functions are integers. Additionally, we compute the twisted traces of Eisenstein series on hyperbolic $3$-space in terms of Dirichlet $L$-functions and divisor sums.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sebasti\'an Herrero, \"Ozlem Imamoglu, Anna-Maria von Pippich, Markus Schwagenscheidt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[La m\'ethode de Shintani et ses variantes]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.01269v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.01269"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.677Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.01269v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We give several versions of Shintani's method for the decomposition into simplicial cones of the fundamental domain of a torus modulo a lattice, and we investigate some applications to the study of Hecke $L$-functions at integer points. In particular, we prove the analytic class number formula for a totally real field, directly at $s=0$.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pierre Colmez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The basis problem for modular forms for the Weil representation]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.01205v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.01205"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.660Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.01205v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The vector valued theta series of a positive-definite even lattice is a modular form for the Weil representation of $\mathrm{SL}_2(\mathbb{Z})$. We show that the space of cusp forms for the Weil representation is generated by such functions. This gives a positive answer to Eichler's basis problem in this case. As applications we derive Waldspurger's result on the basis problem for scalar valued modular forms and give a new proof of the surjectivity of the Borcherds lift based on the analysis of local Picard groups.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Manuel K. -H. M\"uller</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[$A$-analyticity of separatricies of foliations]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.01105v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.01105"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.621Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.01105v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Let $X$ be a smooth quasi-projective surface over a number field $K$, and let $L$ be a foliation on $X$. We prove that if $L$ is closed under $p$-th powers for almost all primes $p$, then any $L$-invariant smooth formal curve is $A$-analytic. Building on prior work of Bost we obtain an algebraicity criterion for those curves.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>St\'ephane Druel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Integral representation of $\mathop{\mathcal R}(s)$ due to Gabcke]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.01028v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.01028"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.589Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.01028v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Gabcke proved a new integral expression for the auxiliary Riemann function \[\mathop{\mathcal R}(s)=2^{s/2}\pi^{s/2}e^{\pi i(s-1)/4}\int_{-\frac12\searrow\frac12} \frac{e^{-\pi i u^2/2+\pi i u}}{2i\cos\pi u}U(s-\tfrac12,\sqrt{2\pi}e^{\pi i/4}u)\,du,\] where $U(\nu,z)$ is the usual parabolic cylinder function.
  We give a new, shorter proof, which avoids the use of the Mordell integral. And we write it in the form \begin{equation}\mathop{\mathcal R}(s)=-2^s \pi^{s/2}e^{\pi i s/4}\int_{-\infty}^\infty \frac{e^{-\pi x^2}H_{-s}(x\sqrt{\pi})}{1+e^{-2\pi\omega x}}\,dx.\end{equation} where $H_\nu(z)$ is the generalized Hermite polynomial.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Juan Arias de Reyna</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distribution of Primitve Lattice Points in Large Dimensions]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.00986v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00986"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.579Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.00986v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We investigate the asymptotic behavior of the distribution of primitive lattice points in a symmetric Borel set $S_d\subset\mathbb R^d$ as $d$ goes to infinity, under certain volume conditions on $S_d$. Our main technique involves exploring higher moment formulas for the primitive Siegel transform. We first demonstrate that if the volume of $S_d$ remains fixed for all $d\in \mathbb N$, then the distribution of the half the number of primitive lattice points in $S_d$ converges, in distribution, to the Poisson distribution of mean $\frac 1 2$. Furthermore, if the volume of $S_d$ goes to infinity subexponentially as $d$ approaches infinity, the normalized distribution of the half the number of primitive lattice points in $S_d$ converges, in distribution, to the Normal distribution $\mathcal N(0,1)$. We also extend these results to the setting of stochastic processes. This work is motivated by the contributions of Rogers (1955), S$\ddot{\text{o}}$dergren (2011) and Str$\ddot{\text{o}}$mbergsson and S$\ddot{\text{o}}$dergren (2019).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jiyoung Han</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On canonical number systems and monogenity of pure number fields]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.00819v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00819"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.478Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.00819v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Let $m$ be a rational integer $(m \neq 0, \pm 1)$ and consider a pure number field $K = \mathbb{Q} (\sqrt[n]{m}) $ with $n \ge 3$. Most papers discussing the monogenity of pure number fields focus only on the case where $m$ is square-free. In this paper, based on a classical theorem of Ore on the prime ideal decomposition \cite{MN92, O}, we study the monogenity of $K$ with $m$ is not necessarily square-free. As an application, several examples of the application of monogenic fields to CNS (Canonical Number System) are shown. In this way, our results extend some parts of previously established results \cite{BFC, BF, HNHCNS}.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hamid Ben Yakkou, Brahim Boudine</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Subspaces spanned by eigenforms with nonvanishing twisted central $L$-values]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.00532v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00532"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.470Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.00532v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we construct explicit spanning sets for two spaces. One is the subspace generated by integral-weight Hecke eigenforms with nonvanishing quadratic twisted central $L$-values. The other is a subspace generated by half-integral weight Hecke eigenforms with certain nonvanishing Fourier coefficients. Along the way, we show that these subspaces are isomorphic via the Shimura lift.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>June Kayath, Connor Lane, Ben Neifeld, Tianyu Ni, Hui Xue</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Rank-Two Case of Local-Global Compatibility for $l = p$]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.00288v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00288"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.461Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.00288v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We prove the classical $l = p$ local-global compatibility conjecture for certain regular algebraic cuspidal automorphic representations of weight 0 for GL$_2$ over CM fields. Using an automorphy lifting theorem, we show that if the automorphic side comes from a twist of Steinberg at $v | l$, then the Galois side has nontrivial monodromy at $v$. Based on this observation, we will give a definition of the Fontaine-Mazur $\mathcal{L}$-invariants attached to certain automorphic representations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuji Yang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monogenity and Power Integral Bases: Recent Developments]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.00374v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00374"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.449Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.00374v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Monogenity is a classical area of algebraic number theory that continues to be actively researched. This paper collects the results obtained over the past few years in this area. Several of the listed results were presented at a series of online conferences titled "Monogenity and Power Integral Bases". We also give a collection of the most important methods used in several of these papers. A list of open problems for further research is also given.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Istv\'an Ga\'al</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monogenic trinomials of the form $x^4+ax^3+d$ and their Galois groups]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.00413v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00413"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.437Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.00413v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Let $f(x)=x^4+ax^3+d\in {\mathbb Z}[x]$, where $ad\ne 0$. Let $C_n$ denote the cyclic group of order $n$, $D_4$ the dihedral group of order 8, and $A_4$ the alternating group of order 12. Assuming that $f(x)$ is monogenic, we give necessary and sufficient conditions involving only $a$ and $d$ to determine the Galois group $G$ of $f(x)$ over ${\mathbb Q}$. In particular, we show that $G=D_4$ if and only if $(a,d)=(\pm 2,2)$, and that $G\not \in \{C_4,C_2\times C_2\}$. Furthermore, we prove that $f(x)$ is monogenic with $G=A_4$ if and only if $a=4k$ and $d=27k^4+1$, where $k\ne 0$ is an integer such that $27k^4+1$ is squarefree. This article extends previous work of the authors on the monogenicity of quartic polynomials and their Galois groups.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joshua Harrington, Lenny Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multiple zeta values with varying constant fields]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.00403v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00403"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.422Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.00403v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multiple zeta values associated with function fields with varying constant fields are dealt with simultaneously. Thakur introduced multiple zeta values in the arithmetic of positive characteristic function fields, and the definition depends on the field of constants of the chosen function field. Using Papanikolas' theory on the relationship between the $t$-motivic Galois group and the periods of a pre-$t$-motive, we show that there exist no algebraic relations which relate multiple zeta values with different constants field.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daichi Matsuzuki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arithmetic properties for generalized cubic partitions and overpartitions modulo a prime]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.00058v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00058"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.373Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.00058v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: A cubic partition is an integer partition wherein the even parts can appear in two colors. In this paper, we introduce the notion of generalized cubic partitions and prove a number of new congruences akin to the classical Ramanujan-type. We emphasize two methods of proofs, one elementary (relying significantly on functional equations) and the other based on modular forms. We close by proving analogous results for generalized overcubic partitions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tewodros Amdeberhan, James A. Sellers, Ajit Singh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probabilistic multi-Stirling numbers of the second kind and probabilistic multi-Lah numbers]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2407.00061v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00061"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T01:08:31.349Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2407.00061v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Assume that the moment generating function of the random vari able Y exists in a neighborhood of the origin. We introduce the probabilistic
  multi-Stirling numbers of the second kind associated with Y and the proba bilistic multi-Lah numbers associated with Y, both of indices (k1,k2,...,kr), by
  means of the multiple logarithm. Those numbers are respectively probabilistic
  extensions of the multi-Stirling numbers of the second kind and the multi-Lah
  numbers which, for (k1,k2,...,kr) = (1,1,...,1), boil down respectively to the
  Stirling numbers of the second and the unsigned Lah numbers. The aim of this
  paper is to study some properties, related identities, recurrence relations and
  explicit expressions of those probabilistic extension numbers in connection with
  several other special numbers]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Taekyun Kim, Dae san Kim</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minimality of the inner automorphism group]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2309.17065v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.17065"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.628Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2309.17065v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: By [6], a minimal group $G$ is called $z$-minimal if $G/Z(G)$ is minimal. In this paper, we present the $z$-Minimality Criterion for dense subgroups with some applications to topological matrix groups. For a locally compact group $G$, let $\operatorname{Inn}(G)$ be the group of all inner automorphisms of $G,$ endowed with the Birkhoff topology. Using a theorem by Goto [14], we obtain our main result which asserts that if $G$ is a connected Lie group and $H\in\{G/Z(G), \operatorname{Inn}(G)\},$ then $H$ is minimal if and only if it is centre-free and topologically isomorphic to $\operatorname{Inn}(G/Z(G)).$ In particular, if $G$ is a connected Lie group with discrete centre, then $\operatorname{Inn}(G)$ is minimal. We prove that a connected locally compact nilpotent group is $z$-minimal if and only if it is compact abelian. In contrast, we show that there exists a connected metabelian $z$-minimal Lie group that is neither compact nor abelian.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dekui Peng, Menachem Shlossberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Construction of Arithmetic Teichmuller Spaces III: A `Rosetta Stone' and a proof of Mochizuki's Corollary 3.12]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2401.13508v3</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.13508"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.620Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2401.13508v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This is a continuation of my work on Arithmetic Teichmuller Spaces (arXiv:2106.11452, arXiv:2210.11635, arXiv:2303.01662, arXiv:2305.10398). This paper establishes a number of important results including (1) a proof Mochizuki's Corollary 3.12 (2) establishes a `Rosetta Stone' for a parallel reading of Mochizuki's Inter-Universal Teichmuller Theory and my Theory of Arithmetic Teichmuller Spaces, and (3) a proof that Mochizuki's gluing of Hodge-Theaters, Frobenioids along prime-strips as described in his theory is naturally provided by the existence of Arithmetic Teichmuller Spaces. (4) Includes the geometric case of Mochizuki's Corollary 3.12 in \S 12.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kirti Joshi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Galois Extensions of Local Fields with a Single Wild Ramification Jump]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2406.14845v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.14845"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.605Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2406.14845v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: For a given unramified extension $K/K_1$ of finite extensions of $\mathbb{Q}_p$, we effectively determine the number of finite Galois extensions $L/K_1$ with maximal unramified subextension $K/K_1$ and a single wild ramification jump at $2$. In fact, we determine explicit formulas in the cases when $K_1/\mathbb{Q}_p$ is totally ramified and when it is unramified. This builds upon the tamely ramified case, which is a classical consequence of Serre's Mass Formula, exhibiting a more restrictive behavior than in the tamely ramified case because the degrees of such extensions are bounded. As a consequence of the calculation, it is also found that the count depends only on the extension $k/k_1$ of residue fields.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Goodman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Compactifications of the Eisenstein ancestral Deligne-Mostow variety]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2403.18345v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.18345"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.595Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2403.18345v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: All arithmetic non-compact ball quotients by Deligne-Mostow's unitary monodromy group arise as sub-ball quotients of either of two spaces called ancestral cases, corresponding to Gaussian or Eisenstein Hermitian forms respectively. In our previous paper, we investigated the compactifications of the Gaussian Deligne-Mostow variety. Here we work on the remaining case, namely the ring of Eisenstein integers, which is related to the moduli space of unordered 12 points on $\mathbb P^1$. In particular, we show that Kirwan's partial resolution of the moduli space is not a semi-toroidal compactification and Deligne-Mostow's period map does not lift to the unique toroidal compactification. We give two interpretations of these phenomena in terms of the log minimal model program and automorphic forms. As an application, we prove that the above two compactifications are not (stacky) derived equivalent, as the $DK$-conjecture predicts. Furthermore, we construct an automorphic form on the moduli space of non-hyperelliptic curves of genus 4, which is isogenous to the Eisenstein Deligne-Mostow variety, giving another intrinsic proof, independent of lattice embeddings, of a result by Casalaina-Martin, Jensen and Laza.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Klaus Hulek, Shigeyuki Kondo, Yota Maeda</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global $\mathbb{A}^1$ degrees of covering maps between modular curves]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2106.10586v4</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2106.10586"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.583Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2106.10586v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Given a projective smooth curve $X$ over any field $k$, we discuss two notions of global $\mathbb{A}^1$ degree of a finite morphism of smooth curves $f: X \to \mathbb{P}^1_k$ satisfying certain conditions. One originates from computing the Euler number of the pullback of the line bundle $\mathscr{O}_{\mathbb{P}^1}(1)$ as a generalization of Kass and Wickelgren's construction of Euler numbers. The other originates from the construction of global $\mathbb{A}^1$ degree of morphisms of projective curves by Kass, Levine, Solomon, and Wickelgren as a generalization of Morel's construction of $\mathbb{A}^1$-Brouwer degree of a morphism $f: \mathbb{P}^1_k \to \mathbb{P}^1_k$. We prove that under certain conditions on $N$, both notions of global $\mathbb{A}^1$ degrees of covering maps between modular curves $X_0(N) \to X(1)$, $X_1(N) \to X(1)$, and $X(N) \to X(1)$ agree to be equal to sums of hyperbolic elements $\langle 1 \rangle + \langle -1 \rangle$ in the Grothendieck-Witt ring $\mathrm{GW}(k)$ for any field $k$ whose characteristic is coprime to $N$ and the pullback of $\mathscr{O}_{\mathbb{P}^1}(1)$ is relatively oriented.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hyun Jong Kim, Sun Woo Park</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On two uniform exponents of approximation related to Wirsing's problem]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2312.08797v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08797"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.489Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2312.08797v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We aim to fill a gap in the proof of an inequality relating two exponents of uniform Diophantine approximation stated in a paper by Bugeaud. We succeed to verify the inequality in several instances, in particular for small dimension. Moreover, we provide counterexamples to generalizations, which contrasts the case of ordinary approximation where such phenomena do not occur. Our results contribute to the understanding of the discrepancy between small absolute values of a polynomial at a given real number and approximation to the number by algebraic numbers of absolutely bounded degree, a fundamental issue in the famous problem of Wirsing and variants.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Johannes Schleischitz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When is the ring of integers of a number field coverable?]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2306.12566v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.12566"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.479Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2306.12566v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: A commutative ring R is said to be coverable if it is the union of its proper subrings and said to be finitely coverable if it is the union of a finite number of them. In the latter case, we denote by {\sigma}(R) the minimal number of required subrings. In this paper, we give necessary and sufficient conditions for the ring of integers A of a given number field to be finitely coverable and a formula for {\sigma}(A) is given which holds when they are met. The conditions are expressed in terms of the existence of common index divisors and (or) common divisors of values of polynomials.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mohamed Ayad, Omar Kihel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A note on Sarnak's density hypothesis for $\textrm{Sp}_4$]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2305.04791v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.04791"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.470Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2305.04791v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this note we prove Sarnak's (spherical) density hypothesis for the full discrete spectrum of the quotients $\Gamma_{\textrm{pa}}(q)\backslash \textrm{Sp}_4(\mathbb{R})$, where $\Gamma_{\textrm{pa}}(q)$ are paramodular groups with square-free level $q$. To derive this estimate we upgrade a density estimate established via the (pre)-Kuznetsov formula, which only accounts for the generic part, using Arthur's parametrization of the discrete spectrum.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edgar Assing</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An analogue of Kida's formula for elliptic curves with additive reduction]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2402.02024v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.02024"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.461Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2402.02024v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We study the Iwasawa theory of $p$-primary Selmer groups of elliptic curves $E$ over a number field $K$. Assume that $E$ has additive reduction at the primes of $K$ above $p$. In this context, we prove that the Iwasawa invariants satisfy an analogue of the Riemann--Hurwitz formula. This generalizes a result of Hachimori and Matsuno. We apply our results to study rank stability questions for elliptic curves in prime cyclic extensions of $\mathbb{Q}$. These extensions are ordered by their absolute discriminant and we prove an asymptotic lower bound for the density of extensions in which the Iwasawa invariants as well as the rank of the elliptic curve is stable.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anwesh Ray, Pratiksha Shingavekar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modular supercuspidal lifts of weight $2$]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2310.11522v2</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.11522"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.449Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2310.11522v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Let $F/\mathbb{Q}$ be any totally real number field and $\frak{N}$ an ideal of its ring of integers of norm $N$ and define, for every even $n$, the $[F:\mathbb{Q}]$-dimensional multiweight $\textbf{n}=(n,...,n)$. We prove that for a non CM Hilbert cuspidal Hecke eigenform for $F$, say $f\in S_{\textbf{k}}(\Gamma_0(\frak{N}))$ with $k>2$ even, and a prime $p>\max\{k+1,6\}$ totally split in $F$ such that $p\nmid N$ and such that the residual mod $p$ representation $\overline{\rho}_f$ satisfies that $\mathrm{SL}_2(\mathbb{F}_p)\subseteq \mathrm{Im}(\overline{\rho}_f)$, there exists a lift $\rho_g$ associated to a Hilbert modular cuspform for $F$, say $g\in S_{\textbf{2}}(\frak{N}p^2,\epsilon)$ for some Nebentypus character $\epsilon$ which is supercuspidal at each prime of $F$ over $p$. We also observe that our techniques provide an alternative proof to the corresponding statement for classical Hecke cuspforms already proved by Khare \cite{khare} with classical techniques. Finally, we take the opportunity to include a corrigenda for \cite{dieulefait} which follows from our main result, which provides a congruence that puts the micro good dihedral prime in the level.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iv\'an Blanco-Chac\'on, Luis Dieulefait</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Norm-equivariant continuous metrics are adelic]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2406.19912v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19912"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.430Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2406.19912v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Yuan and Zhang showed in that any adelic line bundle will induce a norm-equivariant continuous metric of the line bundle on the Berkovich space. We will show the converse that any norm-equivariant continuous metric can be obtained this way. As an application, we will introduce the Monge-Amp\`ere measure on the Berkovich spaces over $ \mathbb{Z} $.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yinchong Song</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heights on 'Hybrid orbits' in Shimura varieties]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2406.20013v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.20013"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.406Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2406.20013v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We prove the 'hybrid conjecture' which is a common generalisation of the Andre\'e-Oort conjecture and the Andr\'e-Pink-Zannier conjecture, in the case of Shimura varieties of abelian type.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rodolphe Richard, Andrei Yafaev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A remark on crystalline cohomology]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2406.19772v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19772"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.399Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2406.19772v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We propose a new approach to crystalline cohomology based on the observation that one can lift smooth algebras uniquely "up to coherent homotopy."]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Moritz Kerz, Georg Tamme</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lefschetz decompositions of Kudla-Millson theta functions]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2406.19921v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19921"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.392Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2406.19921v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the 80's Kudla and Millson introduced a theta function in two variables. It behaves as a Siegel modular form with respect to the first variable, and is a closed differential form on an orthogonal Shimura variety with respect to the other variable. We prove that the Lefschetz decomposition of the cohomology class of that theta function is also its modular decomposition in Eisenstein, Klingen and cuspidal parts. We also show that the image of the Kudla-Millson lift is contained in the primitive cohomology of X. As an application, we deduce dimension formulas for the cohomology of X in low degree. Our results cover the cases of moduli spaces of compact hyperk\"ahler manifolds.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jan Hendrik Bruinier, Riccardo Zuffetti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The dispersion of dilated lacunary sequences, with applications in multiplicative Diophantine approximation]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2406.19802v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19802"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.383Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2406.19802v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Let $(a_n)_{n \in \mathbb{N}}$ be a Hadamard lacunary sequence. We give upper bounds for the maximal gap of the set of dilates $\{a_n \alpha\}_{n \leq N}$ modulo 1, in terms of $N$. For any lacunary sequence $(a_n)_{n \in \mathbb{N}}$ we prove the existence of a dilation factor $\alpha$ such that the maximal gap is of order at most $(\log N)/N$, and we prove that for Lebesgue almost all $\alpha$ the maximal gap is of order at most $(\log N)^{2+\varepsilon}/N$. The metric result is generalized to other measures satisfying a certain Fourier decay assumption. Both upper bounds are optimal up to a factor of logarithmic order, and the latter result improves a recent result of Chow and Technau. Finally, we show that our result implies an improved upper bound in the inhomogeneous version of Littlewood's problem in multiplicative Diophantine approximation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eduard Stefanescu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical heights, periods and the Hurwitz zeta function]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2406.19785v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19785"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.362Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2406.19785v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Let (X,D) be a projective log pair over the ring of integers of a number field such that the log canonical line bundle K_(X,D) or its dual -K_(X,D) is relatively ample. We introduce a canonical height of K_(X,D) (and -K(X,D)) which is finite precisely when the complexifications of K_(X,D) (and -K(X,D)) are K-semistable. When the complexifications are K-polystable, the canonical height is the height of K_(X,D) (and -K(X,D)) wrt any volume-normalized K\"ahler-Einstein metric on the complexifications of K_(X,D) (and -K(X,D)) The canonical height is shown to have a number of useful variational properties. Moreover, it may be expressed as a limit of periods on the N-fold products of the complexifications of X, as N tends to infinity. In particular, using this limit formula, the canonical height for the arithmetic log surfaces (P_1,D) over the integers, where D has at most three components, is computed explicitly in terms of the Hurwitz zeta function and its derivative at s=-1. Combining this explicit formula with previous height formulas for quaternionic Shimura curves yields a procedure for extracting information about the canonical integral models of some Shimura curves, such as wild ramification. Furthermore, explicit formulas for the canonical height of twisted Fermat curves are obtained, implying explicit Parshin type bounds for the Arakelov metric.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rolf Andreasson, Robert J. Berman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Involves averaging arithmetic and integral partial functions over sparse set]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2406.19788v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19788"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.352Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2406.19788v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Let $p$ be a prime number, $k\ge 0$ and $f$ be a class of arithmetic functions satisfying some simple conditions. In this short paper, we study the asymptotical behaviour of summation function $$\psi_{f,k}(x):=\sum_{n\le x}\Lambda (n)\frac{f\left ( \left [ \frac{x}{n} \right ] \right ) }{\left [ \frac{x}{n} \right ]^{k} } ,~~~~~~~~~~~ \pi_{f,k}(x):=\sum_{p\le x}\frac{f\left ( \left [ \frac{x}{p} \right ] \right ) }{\left [ \frac{x}{p} \right ]^{k} } $$ as $x\to \infty $, where $\left [ \cdot \right ] $ is the integral part function, $\Lambda (n)$ is the von Mangoldt function.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zhaoxi Ye, Zhefeng Xu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An entire function defined by Riemann]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2406.19717v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19717"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.342Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2406.19717v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In one of the sheets in Riemann's Nachlass he defines an entire function and connect it with his zeta function. As in many pages in his Nachlass, Riemann is not giving complete proofs. However, I consider that this work is undoubtedly by Riemann. He obtains an $L^\infty$ function whose Fourier transform vanish at the real values $\gamma$ with $\zeta(\frac12+i\gamma)=0$. We give proofs of Riemann formulas. This is an integral representation of the zeta function different from the known ones. I believe this is the first time it has been published.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Juan Arias de Reyna</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Supersingular Ekedahl-Oort strata and Oort's conjecture]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2406.19748v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19748"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.333Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2406.19748v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Let $\mathcal{A}_g$ be the moduli space over $\overline{\mathbb{F}}_p$ of $g$-dimensional principally polarised abelian varieties, where $p$ is a prime. We show that if $g$ is even and $p\geq 5$, then every geometric generic member in the maximal supersingular Ekedahl-Oort stratum in $\mathcal{A}_g$ has automorphism group $\{ \pm 1\}$. This confirms Oort's conjecture in the case of $p\geq 5$ and even $g$.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Valentijn Karemaker, Chia-Fu Yu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new deformation of multiple zeta value]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2406.19641v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19641"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.264Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2406.19641v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce a new deformation of multiple zeta value (MZV). It has one parameter $\omega$ satisfying $0<\omega<2$ and recovers MZV in the limit as $\omega \to +0$. It is defined in the same algebraic framework as a $q$-analogue of multiple zeta value ($q$MZV) by using a multiple integral. We prove that our deformed multiple zeta value satisfies the double shuffle relations which are satisfied by $q$MZVs. We also prove the extended double Ohno relations, which are proved for ($q$)MZVs by Hirose, Sato and Seki, by using a multiple integral whose integrand contains the hyperbolic gamma function due to Ruijsenaars.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yoshihiro Takeyama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upper bounds for shifted moments of Dirichlet $L$-functions to a fixed modulus over function fields]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2406.19606v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19606"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.238Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2406.19606v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we establish sharp upper bounds on shifted moments of the family of Dirichlet $L$-functions to a fixed modulus over function fields. We apply the result to obtain upper bounds on moments of Dirichlet character sums over function fields.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephan Baier, Peng Gao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cohomology of Fuchsian groups and Fourier interpolation]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2406.19511v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19511"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.213Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2406.19511v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We give a new proof of a Fourier interpolation result first proved by Radchenko-Viazovska, deriving it from a vanishing result of the first cohomology of a Fuchsian group with coefficients in the Weil representation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mathilde Gerbelli-Gauthier, Akshay Venkatesh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Well-distribution modulo one and the primes]]></title>
        <id>oai:arXiv.org:2406.19491v1</id>
        <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19491"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T04:46:22.189Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[arXiv:2406.19491v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Let $(p_n)$ denote the sequence of prime numbers, with $2=p_1<p_2<\ldots$. We demonstrate the existence of an irrational number $\alpha$ having the property that the sequence $(\alpha p_n)$ is not well-distributed modulo $1$.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Champagne, T. H. L\^e, Y. -R. Liu, T. D. Wooley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>